Raymond Clapper Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Raymond Clapper Papers 1908-1962 1913-1944
MSS15925
Clapper, Raymond, 1892-1944
75,000 items
249 containers plus 7 oversize
116 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Journalist. Correspondence, memoranda, diaries and writings, notebooks, dispatches, press releases, radio scripts, reports, printed matter, scrapbooks, promotional matter, photographs, and reference material chiefly pertaining to the New Deal and World War II.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Barrett, Edward W. (Edward Ware), 1910-1989--Correspondence.; Capper, Arthur, 1865-1951--Correspondence.; Carlin, George A.--Correspondence.; Clapper family.; Clapper, Raymond, 1892-1944 Racketeering in Washington (1933); Clapper, Raymond, 1892-1944.; Croly, Herbert David, 1869-1930--Correspondence.; Getts, Charles H.--Correspondence.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Howard, Roy Wilson, 1883-1964--Correspondence.; Landon, Alfred M. (Alfred Mossman), 1887-1987--Correspondence.; Landon, Alfred M. (Alfred Mossman), 1887-1987.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; White, William Allen, 1868-1944--Correspondence.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944--Correspondence.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.
Organizations
Gridiron Club (Washington, D.C.); Tennessee Valley Authority.; United States. National Recovery Administration.; United States. Supreme Court.
Subjects
Censorship.; Elections--United States.; Journalism.; Labor.; Neutrality.; Prohibition.; Taxation--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.
Places
Germany.; Great Britain.; Japan.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations--20th century.; United States--Politics and government--1901-1953.; Washington (D.C.)
Occupations
Journalists.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Raymond Clapper, journalist, were given to the Library of Congress by his wife, Olive Clapper, in 1947, 1959, and 1961-1962.
Additional Guides
The papers of Raymond Clapper were described in the Library of Congress Quarterly Journal of Current Acquisitions 6 (May 1949): 87.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Raymond Clapper are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1892, May 30 Born, La Cygne, Kans.
1913 Married Olive Vincent Ewing (died 1968)
1913 1916 Attended University of Kansas, Lawrence, Kans.
1916 Joined staff of Kansas City Star
1923 1928 Night manager and chief political writer, Washington, D.C., bureau, United Press
1929 1934 Chief, Washington, D.C., bureau, United Press
1930 Reported on London naval conference, London, England
1933 Published Racketeering in Washington. Boston: L. C. Page & Co.
1934 1936 Chief, Washington, D.C. bureau, Washington Post
1936 Newspaper column, “Between You and Me,” syndicated by Scripps-Howard
1939 President, Gridiron Club, Washington, D.C.
1942 Began hosting radio program, Mutual Broadcasting System
1944, circa Jan. 29 Killed in airplane crash over the Marshall Islands while war correspondent in the Pacific
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Raymond Clapper (1892-1944) span the years 1908-1962, with the bulk from 1913 to 1944. The collection consists of diaries, letters, memoranda, biographical material, speeches and writings, printed matter, radio scripts, notes, and research and reference material relating primarily to Clapper's career as a journalist. The papers are organized in six series: Personal File; Correspondence; Biographical File; Article, Book, and Speech File; Miscellany; and Reference File. The largest portion is comprised of reference material focusing on the administration of Franklin D. Roosevelt, the New Deal, and World War II.
Important in the collection is material relating to Clapper's book, Racketeering in Washington, an account of graft in governmental departments and agencies, and correspondence between Clapper and H. L. Mencken, editor of the American Mercury, in relation to an article by Clapper on prohibition in Washington, D. C., entitled "Happy Days," published in the American Mercury in January 1927.
Prominent topics in the Reference File include political elections between World War I and World War II, journalism during the interwar period, censorship, presidential administrations from Warren G. Harding through Franklin D. Roosevelt, neutrality and foreign relations with Japan and Germany, the Supreme Court, labor, and the New Deal.
Correspondents include Edward W. Barrett, Arthur Capper. George A. Carlin, Herbert David Croly, Charles H. Getts, Roy Wilson Howard, Alfred M. Landon, H. L. Mencken, William Allen White, and Wendell L. Willkie.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in six series:
Personal File, 1913-1943
Correspondence, 1913-1959
Biographical File, 1940-1944
Article, Book, and Speech File, 1911-1944
Miscellany, 1908-1960
Reference File, 1913-1962
Container List
- Personal File, 1913-1943 (Box 1-42)
  Diaries, personal records, promotion file, Gridiron Club material, foreign travel files, and scrapbooks containing notebooks, correspondence, near-print, and printed matter, manuscripts and typescripts of writings, and newspaper clippings.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Diaries (Box 1)
    - 1913-1914
    - 1915 (Box 2)
    - 1916 (Box 3)
    - 1916-1917 (Box 4)
    - 1917-1918 (Box 5)
    - 1918-1920 (Box 6)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 7)
    - 1932-1939 (Box 8)
    - 1940-1942 (Box 9)
  - Personal records (Box 10)
    - 1914-1924
    - 1925-1932 (Box 11)
    - 1933 (Box 12)
    - 1933-1934 (Box 13)
    - 1935 (Box 14)
    - 1936 (Box 15)
    - 1936 (Box 16)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 17)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 18)
    - 1939-1943, undated (Box 19)
  - Promotion file (Box 20)
    - 1936-1940
    - 1940-1942 (Box 21)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 22)
  - Memoranda (Box 23)
    - 1942-1943
  - Notebooks (Box 24)
    - 1934-1937
    - 1937-1940 (Box 25)
    - 1940-1943 (Box 26)
  - Gridiron Club, Washington, D.C. (Box 27)
    - 1925-1933
    - 1934-1935 (Box 28)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 29)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 30)
    - 1939 (Box 31)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 32)
    - 1940-1943 (Box 33)
  - Foreign travel (Box 34)
    - 1937
    - 1941 (Box 35)
    - 1942 (Box 36)
    - 1943 (Box 37)
    - 1943 (Box 38)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 39)
    - 1929-1930
    - 1930 (Box 40)
    - 1930-1931 (Box 41)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 42)
- Correspondence, 1913-1959 (Box 43-51)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent.
  - 1913-1917 (Box 43)
  - 1917 (Box 44)
  - 1918 (Box 45)
  - 1919-1923 (Box 46)
  - 1924-1932 (Box 47)
  - 1934-1938 (Box 48)
  - 1939-1941 (Box 49)
  - 1942 (Box 50)
  - 1943-1944, undated (Box 51)
  - 1945, 1959, to Olive Ewing Clapper (wife)
- Biographical File, 1940-1944 (Box 52-55)
  Correspondence, near-print and printed matter, and newspaper clippings.
  - 1940-1944 (Box 52)
  - 1944 (Box 53)
  - 1944 (Box 54)
  - 1944 (Box OV 55)
- Article, Book, and Speech File, 1911-1944 (Box 56-96)
  Holograph and typewritten drafts and copies of Clapper's newspaper writings, magazine articles, books, and speeches and radio scripts, including related correspondence, clippings, and other material.
  Arranged by type of writing and material and therein chronologically.
  - Newspaper file (Box OV 56)
    - Column
      - 1934
      - 1935 (Box OV 57)
      - 1936 (Box OV 58)
      - 1937 (Box 59)
      - 1938 (Box 60)
      - 1938 (Box 61)
      - 1939 (Box OV 62)
      - 1940-1942 (Box 63)
      - 1942-1944 (Box 64)
    - Warren G. Harding (Box OV 65)
      - 1920-1921
      - 1920-1924 (Box 66)
    - Nepotism (Box 67)
      - 1931-1932
      - 1932 (Box 68)
      - 1932 (Box 69)
      - 1932 (Box 70)
    - Stories (Box 71)
      - 1911-1924
      - 1925-1931 (Box 72)
      - 1931 (Box 73)
      - 1932 (Box 74)
      - 1932 (Box 75)
      - 1933 (Box 76)
      - 1933-1943, undated (Box 77)
  - Magazine file (Box 78)
    - General
      - 1918-1927, including correspondence with H. L. Mencken in relation to Happy Days, an article by Clapper on prohibition in Washington, D. C., American Mercury, Jan. 1927
      - 1928-1935 (Box 79)
      - 1936-1938 (Box 80)
      - 1939-1940 (Box 81)
      - 1941 (Box 82)
      - 1942-1943 (Box 83)
    - Review of Reviews, 1933-1937 (Box 84)
    - Miscellaneous
  - London Daily Mail, 1940-1942 (Box 85)
    - Graft, 1932-1935
    - General
  - Book file (Box 86)
    - Racketeering in Washington
      - 1933-1934
      - 1933-1934 (Box 87)
    - Unpublished and untitled book, 1939-1942 (Box 88)
  - Speeches (Box 89)
    - 1929-1937
    - 1937-1938 (Box 90)
    - 1939 (Box 91)
    - 1940-1943 (Box 92)
  - Radio scripts (Box 93)
    - 1932-1942
    - 1942-1943 (Box 94)
    - 1943 (Box 95)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 96)
- Miscellany, 1908-1960 (Box 97-98)
  Clapper Award winners, memorabilia, near-print and printed matter, newspaper clippings, and photographs.
  Organized by type of material.
  - Raymond Clapper Award winners, 1945-1960 (Box 97)
  - General
  - Memorabilia
  - Near print, 1924-1938
  - Newspaper clippings
  - Photographs
  - Printed matter
    - 1908-1910
    - 1911-1945, undated (Box 98)
- Reference File, 1913-1962 (Box 99-256)
  Correspondence, near-print and printed matter, and newspapers clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject, name of person, or organization, and therein by type of material, which is then organized chronologically except for newspaper clippings.
  - Africa, 1942-1943 (Box 99)
  - Agriculture (Box 100)
    - 1935-1939
    - 1934-1942 (Box 101)
  - Aiken, George, D., 1937-1943
  - Alabama, 1937-1940
  - Alaska, 1942
  - Aluminum, 1933-1937
  - American Liberty League, 1934-1936 (Box 102)
  - Arizona, 1936
  - Arkansas, 1938
  - Arnold, Henry Harley, 1942
  - Arnold, Thurman, 1938-1941
  - Ashurst, Henry F., 1934-1940
  - Aster, Vincent, 1934 (Box 103)
  - Austin, Warren, 1941
  - Australia, 1941-1942
  - Automobile industry, 1935-1938
  - Aviation
    - 1938-1943
    - 1940-1943 (Box 104)
  - Ball, J. H., 1944-1945
  - Banking
    - 1932-1935
    - 1933-1939 (Box 105)
  - Bankhead, Brothers, 1935
  - Barkley, Alben W., 1937
  - Barton, Bruce, 1937-1938
  - Baruch, Bernard M., 1934
  - Berle, A. A. (1895-1971), 1934-1939
  - Board of Economic Warfare, 1942
  - Biddle, Francis Beverly, 1934
  - Black, Hugo LaFayette, 1937-1938 (Box 106)
  - Borah, William Edgar, 1935-1939 (Box 107)
  - Brain Trust
  - Bricker, John W.
  - Budget
    - 1934-1935
    - 1934-1943 (Box 108)
  - Bullitt, William C., 1934-1941
  - Bureaucracy, 1935-1939
  - Byrnes, James, 1940
  - Byrnes, Joe, 1935
  - Cabinet, 1932-1933 (Box 109)
  - California, 1938-1939
  - Canada
  - Casualties, 1943
  - Censorship
    - 1933-1936
    - 1934-1938 (Box 110)
    - 1938 (Box 111)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 112)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 113)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 114)
  - China, 1937-1943
  - Civilian defense, 1942 (Box 115)
  - Clark, Bennett, 1936-1938
  - Cleveland, Ohio, 1939
  - Colorado, 1938-1939
  - Columbia River, 1934-1935
  - Bonneville Dam and Coulee Dam
  - Communism, 1936-1940 (Box 116)
  - Congress
    - 1935-1936
    - 1937-1942 (Box 117)
  - Connecticut
    - 1938
    - 1940 (Box 118)
  - Coolidge, Calvin
    - General, 1925-1938
    - Speeches, 1924-1928 (Box 119)
  - Corcoran, Thomas G., 1937-1938
  - Corporations (government), 1934-1935
  - Coughlin, Charles E., 1934-1940 (Box 120)
  - Coy, Wayne, 1941
  - Cromwell, James H. R., 1940
  - Cummings, Homer S., 1934-1939
  - Curley, James, 1936
  - Curtis, Charles and Dolly Gann, 1934
  - Davies, Joseph Edward, 1936-1939 (Box 121)
  - Davis, Chester C., 1934
  - Davis, Norman, 1935
  - Declaration of Independence, 1925
  - Defense
    - 1938-1941
    - 1939-1940 (Box 122)
    - 1939-1941 (Box 123)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 124)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 125)
  - Delaware, 1938-1940
  - Democracy, 1934-1939 (Box 126)
  - Democrats
    - 1933-1940
    - 1937-1940 (Box 127)
  - Demagogues, 1940
  - Dogs
  - Donahey, Vic, 1934
  - Doughton, R. L., 1934-1935
  - Douglass, Lewis W., 1934-1936
  - Douglas, William D., 1939
  - Douney, Sheridan, 1939
  - DuPonts, 1939
  - Early, Stephen I., 1937-1940 (Box 128)
  - Eastman, Joe (Interstate Commerce Commission), 1937
  - Eccles, Marriner S.
    - 1935-1936
    - 1937
  - Economic defense, 1941
  - Edward VIII, King of Great Britain, 1936
  - Elections
    - 1932-1934
    - 1934-1938 (Box 129)
    - 1939-1941 (Box 130)
    - 1942-1943
    - Including primaries, 1925-1927
  - Eliot, Thomas Hopkinson (Social Security Board), 1937
  - Ethiopia, 1935
  - Ezekiel, Mordecai, 1934
  - Fall, Albert B., 1935
  - Fall-Doheny Case, 1924-1927
  - Farley, James A., 1934-1940 (Box 131)
  - Foreign trade, 1934-1939 (Box 132)
  - Foreign affairs, 1936-1938 (Box 133)
  - Foreign ideologies, 1939
  - The forgotten man, 1934
  - Fish, Hamilton (1888-1991), 1934-1942
  - Florida, 1940
  - Flynn, Edward J., 1941
  - France
    - 1937-1941
    - 1934-1940 (Box 134)
  - Frank, Jerome, 1936
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1940
  - Garner, John N., 1939
  - General, 1931-1939 (Box 135)
  - George, Walter F., 1940
  - Georgia, 1938-1940
  - Geography and politics, 1942
  - Strategy
  - Germany
    - 1934-1938
    - 1934-1938 (Box 136)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 137)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 138)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 139)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 140)
    - 1941 (Box 141)
  - Glass, Carter, 1934-1939
  - Gold, 1933-1940
  - Great Britain (Box 142)
    - 1937-1938
    - 1937-1939 (Box 143)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 144)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 145)
    - 1941-1943 (Box 146)
  - Greenland and Iceland, 1941 (Box 147)
  - Greenway, Isabella, 1935
  - Guffey, Joseph, 1938
  - Hamilton, John, 1936-1938
  - Harding, Warren G.
    - 1920-1926
    - 1921-1937 (Box 148)
    - 1923 (Box 149)
    - 1920 (Box OV 150)
  - Harriman, Florence Jaffray Hurst, 1937-1940 (Box 151)
  - Harvey, W. H., 1930
  - Hearst, William Randolph, 1936
  - Henderson, Leon, and Democrats, 1942
  - Hillman, Sidney, 1940
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell (1841-1935), 1935
  - Hoover, Herbert
    - 1927-1930
    - 1929
    - 1934-1941
    - General introduction, 1930
    - Inaugural address
    - Presidential inaugural
  - Hoover commissions, 1930-1931 (Box 152)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1940 (Box 153)
  - Hopkins, Harry L.
    - 1934-1939
    - 1939
  - Housing, 1937-1940
  - Hull, Cordell, 1935-1940
  - Hurda, Emil, 1932-1936
  - Hyde, Arthur M., 1930
  - Ickes, Harold L. (1874-1952), 1934-1938 (Box 154)
  - Idaho, 1938
  - Illinois
    - 1938
    - 1940
  - Inaugurations, presidential
    - 1925
    - 1929
    - 1929 (Box 155)
    - 1933
      - General
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
      - Washington Star
      - New York Times
  - India
    - 1942
    - 1942-1943 (Box 156)
  - Indiana, 1938-1940
  - Industry, Wilmington, Del., 1940
  - Inflation and prices
    - 1941
    - 1941 (Box 157)
  - Interior Department, 1932
  - Iowa, 1938-1940
  - Italy, 1936-1940
  - Jackson, Robert Houghwout, 1937-1940 (Box 158)
  - Japan
    - 1934-1940
    - 1925-1940 (Box 159)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 160)
  - Jefferson, Thomas, 1938
  - Jews, 1939
  - Johnson, Edwin C., 1936
  - Johnson, Hugh S., 1934-1926
  - Johnson, Louis, 1936
  - Jones, Jesse, 1934-1942
  - Judiciary, 1931-1937
  - Kansas, 1937-1938
  - Kennedy, Joseph P., 1933-1938
  - Kentucky, 1938-1939
  - Journalism (Box 161)
    - 1922-1938
    - Miscellany, undated (Box 162)
  - Knox, Frank, 1935-1941 (Box 163)
  - Labor
    - 1940
    - 1936-1938 (Box 164)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 165)
    - 1937 (Box 166)
    - 1938 (Box 167)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 168)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 169)
    - 1938-1942 (Box 170)
    - 1941 (Box 171)
  - LaFollette, Robert M. (1895-1953), 1936-1940 (Box 172)
  - La Guardia, Fiorello H., 1937
  - Landon, Alfred M.
    - 1934-1935
    - 1936-1940
    - 1936 (Box 173)
    - 1937-1943 (Box 174)
  - League of Nations, 1935-1939 (Box 175)
  - Left-wing movements (domestic), 1939
  - Lend-lease operations
  - Lenroot roll call, and Paul R. Mallon, 1924-1929
  - Lewis, John L., 1936-1937
  - Libel, 1934-1936 (Box 176)
  - Liberalism, 1936-1938
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1938-1939
  - Lincoln, Neb., 1939
  - Lindbergh, Charles A., 1934-1940
  - Lobby
    - 1934-1939
    - 1930 (Box 177)
  - Local bosses, 1939-1940
  - Lodge, 1924
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot (1902-1985), 1936-1938
  - Long, Huey P., 1934-1935
  - Longworth, Alice Roosevelt, 1935
  - Louisiana, 1938-1939
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1942
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1939
  - McNary, Charles L., 1934-1940
  - McNutt, Paul, 1938-1940 (Box 178)
  - Maine, 1938-1940 (Box 179)
  - Maloney, Francis T.
  - Manpower and selective service, 1943
  - Maps, 1939-1942
  - Marshall, George C., 1940
  - Martin, Joe, 1938-1939
  - Maryland, 1938-1940
  - Massachusetts, 1938-1940
  - Means, Gaston B., 1938
  - Mellon, Andrew, 1934-1935 (Box 180)
  - Messiahs, 1939
  - Michigan, 1937-1939
  - Military strength
  - Minnesota, 1938-1940
  - Mississippi, 1938-1939
  - Missouri, 1938-1940
  - Monetary stabilization, 1943 (Box 181)
  - Monopoly hearing data
    - 1938-1939
    - 1940-1941 (Box 182)
  - Montana, 1937-1938
  - Moore, Harry A., 1938
  - Morgan, J. Pierpont., 1937
  - Morgenthau, Henry (1856-1946), 1919-1933
  - Murphy, Frank, 1936
  - National emergency, 1934
  - National income, 1932-1939
  - National Recovery Administration (Box 183)
    - 1934-1937
    - 1934 (Box 184)
    - NRA decisions for comment, 1935 (Box 185)
  - National Resources Board, 1934
  - Nebraska, 1938-1940
  - Negroes, 1942
  - Nepotism, 1936-1939
  - Neutral rights
    - 1935-1936
    - 1935-1937 (Box 186)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 187)
  - Neutrality
    - 1939-1940
    - 1940-1941 (Box 188)
    - 1941 (Box 189)
  - Nevada, 1938-1940
  - New Hampshire, 1938-1940
  - New Jersey, 1938-1940
  - New Mexico, 1938-1940
  - New York
    - 1938
    - 1938-1942 (Box 190)
  - Norris, George W., 1935-1942
  - North Carolina, 1938-1940
  - North Dakota, 1938-1940
  - Nye, Gerald P., 1937
  - Ohio, 1938-1940
  - Oil, 1934-1943
  - Oklahoma, 1938-1940 (Box 191)
  - Oliphant, Herman, 1939
  - O'Mahoney, Joseph C., undated
  - Oregon, 1938
  - Ostrander, Donald, CARE, 1962
  - Panama Steam Ship Co., 1933
  - Passamaquoddy project, Maine, 1936
  - Patronage, 1934-1935
  - Peace talk, 1940-1941
  - Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, 1942
  - Pennsylvania
    - 1936-1938
    - 1939-1940 (Box 192)
  - Pepper, Claude, 1940
  - Perkins, Frances, 1932-1939
  - Perkins, Milo, 1942
  - Pershing, John J., 1938
  - Pittman, Key, 1936
  - Population, 1936-1940
  - Poland, 1938-1939
  - Political miscellany
    - 1916
    - 1924-1925
    - 1926
    - 1926-1930 (Box 193)
    - 1930 (Box 194)
    - 1930-1935 (Box 195)
    - 1935-1939 (Box 196)
  - Postwar (Box 197)
    - 1941-1943
    - 1941-1942 (Box 198)
    - 1941-1943 (Box 199)
  - Power of president, 1937-1939
  - Price and monopoly, 1935-1941 (Box 200)
  - Prohibition, 1931-1941
  - Propaganda causes (Box 201)
    - 1937-1941
    - 1941 (Box 202)
  - Public Health Service
    - 1944-1945
    - 1944-1945 (Box 203)
  - Public opinion, 1915-1938 (Box 204)
  - Radio, 1934-1939
  - Railroads
    - 1925
    - 1933-1938 (Box 205)
  - Rainey, Henry T., 1934 (Box 206)
  - Raskob, John J., 1936
  - Raw materials, 1939-1942
  - Rayburn, Sam, 1941
  - Reconstruction Finance Corp., 1935-1936
  - Reed, James A., undated (Box 207)
  - Reorganization, 1937-1940
  - Republican Party
    - National committee, 1934-1935
    - National convention, 1936 (Box 208)
  - Republicans
    - 1936
    - 1935 (Box 209)
    - Pre-convention, 1940
  - Rhode Island, 1938-1940
  - Richberg, Donald R., 1934-1940
  - Ritter, Halstead L., impeachment, 1936
  - Robert, L. W. (“Chip”), 1935
  - Robinson, Frances, 1934
  - Robinson, Joseph T., 1933-1936
  - Rocha, Josephine, 1939
  - Rockefeller, John D. (1839-1937), 1937
  - Rogers, James Harvey, 1934
  - Roll calls, 1934
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box 210)
    - Personal
      - 1933-1936
      - 1936-1937 (Box 211)
      - 1937-1938 (Box 212)
      - 1938-1939 (Box 213)
      - 1940-1942 (Box 214)
      - 1942-1943 (Box 215)
    - Speeches (Box 216)
      - 1932-1935
      - 1936 (Box 217)
      - 1937-1939 (Box 218)
    - Speeches and third term, 1939-1940 (Box 219)
    - Third term, 1937 (Box 220)
    - Fourth term, 1942
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor
  - Roosevelt, James and Elliot
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (1887-1944), 1913-1936 (Box 221)
  - Roper, Daniel C., 1934
  - Rubber and raw materials, 1943
  - Salary, 1936-1938
  - Savings and investment hearings, 1939-1940 (monopoly committee)
  - Scientific articles, popular, 1925
  - Scripps-Howard, 1938-1942
  - Scripps, Robert, undated
  - Secret Service, 1925-1935
  - Shipping and submarines, 1942-1943
  - Silver, 1935-1939 (Box 222)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1933-1934
  - Smith, Alfred E., 1936
  - Smith, Gerald L. K., 1936
  - Smoot, Reed, 1930-1932
  - Social insurance, 1938-1939
  - Socialists, 1936
  - Society, 1929
  - Solomon Islands campaign, 1942-1943 (Box 223)
  - South Carolina, 1938-1940
  - South Dakota, 1938
  - Soviet Union
    - 1934-1938
    - 1939-1943 (Box 224)
    - 1940-1943 (Box 225)
  - Spain, Francisco Franco regime, 1940-1943
  - Stassen, Harold, 1942-1943
  - Statistics
    - 1934-1935
    - 1937-1940 (Box 226)
  - Steel
    - 1935-1943
    - 1935-1943 (Box 227)
  - Stimson, Henry L., 1940
  - Subsidies, 1932-1933
  - Supreme Court (Box 228)
    - 1923-1939
    - 1930-1936 (Box 229)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 230)
    - 1935-1938 (Box 231)
    - 1936-1941 (Box 232)
    - 1936-1941 (Box 233)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 234)
    - 1936-1938 (Box 235)
    - 1937 (Box 236)
  - Sweden, 1943
  - Taft, Charles P., 1937
  - Taft, Robert A. (1889-1953), 1939-1943
  - Taft, William H., 1937
  - Talmadge, Eugene, 1935-1936 (Box 237)
  - Tammany, 1933-1938
  - Tariff, 1934-1936
  - Taxes
    - 1933-1938
    - 1933-1940 (Box 238)
    - 1935-1939 (Box 239)
    - 1940-1943
  - Tax evasion, 1937
  - Tennessee, 1939-1940
  - Tennessee Valley Authority
    - 1933-1938
    - 1933-1941 (Box 240)
    - 1936-1940 (Box 241)
  - Texas, 1938-1940
  - Thomas, Elmer, 1934
  - Tin, undated
  - Tinkham, George H., 1934
  - Tobacco, 1935
  - Townsend Plan
    - 1936-1938
    - 1938 (Box 242)
  - Treasury, 1933
  - Troyanovsky, Alexander A., 1934
  - Truman, Harry S., 1934
  - Trusts, 1926-1927
  - Tugwell, Rexford Guy, 1934-1935
  - Turkey, 1941
  - Two-thirds rule, 1932
  - Tydings, Millard, 1935
  - United States foreign policy (Box 243)
    - 1933-1940
    - 1933-1943 (Box 244)
  - Vandenberg, Arthur, 1934-1940
  - Utah, 1938
  - Vermont, 1940 (Box 245)
  - Veterans, 1934-1936
  - Virginia
    - 1938
    - 1938-1939
  - Voice of the people, 1930, 1930m
  - Wadsworth, James W., 1934
  - Wagner, Robert F., 1937
  - Wakefield, 1924-1928
  - Walker, Frank C., 1934-1935
  - Wallace, Henry A., 1934-1940 (Box 246)
  - War Department, 1931-1942 (Box 247)
  - War Production, 1942
  - Warren, Earl, 1943
  - Washington state
    - 1924-1929
    - 1927 (Box 248)
  - Washington, D.C., 1925-1940 (Box 249)
  - Washington, George, 1937
  - Weir, E. T., 1936-1940 (Box 250)
  - Welles, Sumner, 1941-1943
  - West Virginia, 1938-1939
  - Wheeler, Burton K., 1939-1943
  - Whispering campaign, 1936 (Box 251)
  - White House, 1924-1936
  - Willkie, Wendell L.
    - Campaign, 1940
    - General
      - 1939-1940
      - 1939-1940 (Box 252)
      - 1939-1943 (Box 253)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1924-1931 (Box 254)
  - Winant, John R., 1941
  - Wisconsin, 1938-1940
  - Work relief (Box 255)
    - 1935-1936
    - 1935-1938 (Box 256)
  - World War I, 1928-1939